Guide to the Eric Vettel collection of Cetus Corporation materials M2113
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Eric Vettel collection of Cetus Corporation materials
1969-1986
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Vettel, Eric
M2113
2 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Business records from the Cetus Corporation and research notes from author and historian Eric Vettel.
Content Description
Business records from the Cetus Corporation, one of the first biotechnology companies in the United States. Cetus was founded in Berkeley, California in 1971 by Ronald E. Cape, Peter Farley, and Donald A. Glaser, and was sold to Chiron in 1991. The collection includes their original business plan, documents related to a 1981 public offering as well as material concerning business operations, finances, board, management, and competition. Eric Vettel, who wrote a 2006 history of biotechnology and Cetus ("Biotech: The Countercultural Origins of an Industry"), assembled this material and donated it to Stanford along with his research notes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eric J. Vettel, 2016.
Biotechnology industries -- California; Vettel, Eric; Vettel, Eric; Cetus Corporation
- Cetus board meeting, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Interviews (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Interviews 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cetus Passage (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CRI/Public/Competition, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Don Glaser-Sally's files (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ward Glaser articles/Science, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Glaser Bing (Box 1, Folder 8)
- IPO memo-prep, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Japanese compact. Green cross (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Media/PR Cetus on RDNA, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- School of event IPO Cetus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Going public cetus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Going public cetus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Standard Oil + cetus stock, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- IFN Cetus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- IFN, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Flakes, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Policy/IPO, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- IFN, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Collabor, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Interferon Cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Caltech Auto mach seq. Cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cetus/Gelasev research, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Flakes Cetus, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Employ dispute cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Stock holders-cetus (Box 2, Folder 11)
- All consult collab cetus, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Historical overview-cape, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Flakes cetus, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Contact research-ICI Cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Article biotechnology (Box 2, Folder 16)
- PR Cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Road Show, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Collab w/ IML Cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Colab. in China. Cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Stock recom. cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Share holders mtg. cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Annual repost cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Media, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Flakes-cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Road show cetus, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- MEA/HLV collab. cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- HEP-B Stanford/Cohen cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Searle (Rumsfeld) collab. cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Proprietary and confidential information on cetus agricultural technology for exclusive use of W.R. Grace & co., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Medga cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Hist overview-cape cetus, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- My typed nites; cetus (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Sally Chronology (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Hybritech 1st bit plan (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Foundry BOD hydritech, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Hybr. Stock sale art, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Hybritech cetus papers (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Paul Aebersold antogen specific t-cell, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- IFN Colby/Denney cetus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lederberg advice post-cetus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Heal the drug delivery, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Flakes-cetus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Schering AO RDNA. Cetus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Cetus annual repost cetus, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- BOD mtg/research plan, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Insulin (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Public+policy, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Jobs/positions cetus, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Flakes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Compensation cetus, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Incentive plan, 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Alkene project, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Expansion cetus, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- New manager cetus, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Evaluation of cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Road show cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Media-cetus UK. cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Media-cetus. Past+future cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- UK trip of roadshow cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- IFN-burr/wale collab. cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- IFN collab., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Public ret. policy, 1973/1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Collab opport, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Bogue + private work (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Senate hear/cape cetus (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Underwriting agreements. cetus, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Cetus, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Lederberg articles (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Policy/public general, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Cape present cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Accounting, cost, cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Public opinion-congress, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Project cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Glaser student cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- IFN-sloan collab., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- IFN, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- P3 architect (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Financial state review cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Destruction/schering, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Gluconic acid collab. cetus, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- GNE annual repost, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- GNE 1980 annual repost (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Blood clots of monocloud GNE (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Schering-plough biogen (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Financing (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Science/UC's (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Cohen articles, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cetus AG+Grace (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Competition, GNE, cetus (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Genius glaser (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Cape-Biz background, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Essay "Silicon Valley" (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Glaser Oh Q's (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Don Glaser-bro (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Glaser-old history. Gen articles (biography) (Box 4, Folder 27)
- A.P Grant applic. Glaser (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Biotech book images (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Glaser papers (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Hosp. zone scan. Cetus, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Acad. Art + conf Glaser cetus, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Cetus archive papers tobacco (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Confidential (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Financials cetus, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Schering contract, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Financial cetus, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Financial cetus, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Board MTG-motiv., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- RDMA, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- RDMA-thought consult (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Employ work stat. Cetus, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- GNR. Insulin... Synthetic-bad (Box 5, Folder 10)